<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Art on Zack&#39;s Notablog</title><link>https://yakczar.com/tags/art/</link><description>Recent content in Art on Zack&#39;s Notablog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:25:57 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yakczar.com/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Painting from computer-generated primitives</title><link>https://yakczar.com/painting-primitives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 18:25:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://yakczar.com/painting-primitives/</guid><description>Computers can do many amazing things with art, especially with the advent of neural networks1. In 2016, I saw some computer-generated art that inspired me to generate art as a human. The art I saw was a rendition of photos in primitives. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example (For much more, just follow @primitivepic):
These kinds of photos were generated using a computer program that tries to replicate a photo by slowly building up primitive shapes (ellipses, rectangles, triangles) of a single color until eventually enough different shapes and colors converge on the original image.</description></item><item><title>Watercoloring with neural networks</title><link>https://yakczar.com/watercolor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 05:48:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://yakczar.com/watercolor/</guid><description>Can a neural network help me improve my art? Could I take a photo, paint it, and then use a neural network to render the original photo in the style of my painting to make it better? Could I learn something from it?
Some background I started thinking about these questions because I’ve been reading about neural networks, and I’ve seen a lot of these neural networks create new works of art by rendering a photo in the style of a famous painting1.</description></item></channel></rss>