<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Senses on schollz blog</title>
    <link>https://schollz.github.io/tags/senses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Senses on schollz blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://schollz.github.io/tags/senses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How can potential transplant donors be identified by their sense of smell?</title>
      <link>https://schollz.github.io/sense-of-smell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schollz.github.io/sense-of-smell/</guid>
      <description>Researchers discover a new way of discovering bone marrow transplants matches by using only their sense of smell! I just recently wrote about a recent discovery that find people can smell without their noses (hint they use their skin) . Well, a new article by Lavi Secundo et. al. finds that the nose is still useful, since the olfactory receptors in a nose are so unique that they can distinguish humans from one another and this distinction can be used to find bone marrow transplant donors!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does your skin act like a nose?</title>
      <link>https://schollz.github.io/skin-as-nose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://schollz.github.io/skin-as-nose/</guid>
      <description>We smell with our nose, or do we? Recently scientists have found that for some smells we can smell with our skin, and those smells can heal wounds. Our ability to smell requires olfactory receptors which are often found in the nose. Humans have about 400 of these receptors, 350 of which are in the nose, while others have been shown to exist in sperm, the prostate, intestines, and kidneys.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>