<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Physics on schollz blog</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/tags/physics/</link><description>Recent content in Physics on schollz blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://schollz.github.io/tags/physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do interleaved phonebooks stay together?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/interleaved-phonebooks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/interleaved-phonebooks/</guid><description>We have all marveled at the astonishing feat of being able to hold up massive amounts of weight with only phonebooks. Mythbusters even went so far as to use tanks to try to pull apar the phone books. Since then, however, the origin of this phenomenon has remained very elusive and escaped full description.
It was first thought that the mechanism is due to the friction between interleaving pages. A new paper by Hector Alacron and colleagues1 finds that this explaination is incorrect and offer a more intuitive and more predictive explaination.</description></item><item><title>How do ants survive in the heat in the Sahara desert?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/ants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/ants/</guid><description>There is a class of ants that survive in the Sahara desert despite it being one of the hottest places on Earth, where the surface temperature can reach up to 150 degrees Fahrenheit. These ants, called &amp;ldquo;silver ants&amp;rdquo; or Cataglyphis bombycina have recently been found to harbor specialized triangular hairs that enable them significantly increased thermoregulation, as reported in the recent issue of Science. [1] Though the surface of the desert exceeds 150F, the ants can keep an internal temperature of 120F.</description></item><item><title>How is the brain like a ball of crumpled paper?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/brain-folds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/brain-folds/</guid><description>This paper shows that the crumpling of our brain is much simpler than we thought . The crumples in our brain are just like the ones in crumpled paper. Bruno Mota and Suzana Herculano-Houzel find that our brain shares something in common with crumbled balls of paper - both did not evolve their folds in response to natural selection of their environment.
So what? This paper shows that the crumpling of our brain is much simpler than we thought.</description></item></channel></rss>