<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on schollz blog</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on schollz blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://schollz.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Favorite books of 2017</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/books-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/books-2017/</guid><description>Illumination in the Flatwoods by Joe Hutto
My favorite book of 2017. I never knew how amazing turkeys were until I read this book. There is a movie by the same name that also is amazing, as they were able to recapitulate a lot which occurred in the book.
Library at Mount Char by Scott Hawkins
My second-favorite book of 2017. The premise is bizarre, but the books twists in a much more bizarre way than imaginable.</description></item><item><title>Favorite music of 2017</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/music-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 09:41:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/music-2017/</guid><description>I have been using Spotify Discovery Weekly playlists, Sound Opinions podcast, and the NPR All Songs Considered podcast to discover all sorts of great music.
Orchestral Variations by Minor Victories
From what I understand, this is a symphonic cover album of a indie rock album. I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to the rock album a little and I can&amp;rsquo;t understand why this orchestral version is so much better.
Men I Trust by Men I Trust</description></item><item><title>Use social media without being social</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/using-social-media/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/using-social-media/</guid><description>Social media seems to be more about creating a persona that voicing your thoughts and ideas. Not thinking about public opinion enables you too emit thoughts without fear of judgment, which is why I&amp;rsquo;ve found it helpful to use social media without being social.
I make accounts on social media that are totally protected. I don&amp;rsquo;t follow anyone or let anyone follow me. I keep the account locked so no one can even visit it.</description></item><item><title>OSS divisions</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/oss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/oss/</guid><description>There are two reasons I think its good for everyone to have a good division between &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;corporate&amp;rdquo; use for open-source software (OSS):
1. If you, the OSS maintainer, are compensated, everyone benefits.
While your time spent coding your OSS is valuable, I think the frictionless delivery of new features and bug fixes is something that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go away.
Since I&amp;rsquo;m not actively supporting you financially to work on this, I can only hope that someone does so I can benefit.</description></item><item><title>Beware of the free trial</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/beware-of-the-free-trial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 09:51:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/beware-of-the-free-trial/</guid><description>tldr: A big company billed me for years without my knowledge. However, they unknowingly violated their own Conditions of Use so I got my money refunded
I was looking at my bank statement last week and something was wrong. I had a charge of $15 for The Service (a big company that I will not name here), a service I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used for years after I tried one of their free items.</description></item><item><title>Moderation</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/moderation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 09:43:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/moderation/</guid><description>This quote by Oscar Wilde,
Everything in moderation, including moderation
is wrong.
By doing everything in moderation &amp;ndash; including moderation &amp;ndash; then that means you are overdoing moderation, which the quote forbids.
It should be amended:
Everything in moderation, excepting moderation</description></item><item><title>How do interleaved phonebooks stay together?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/interleaved-phonebooks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/interleaved-phonebooks/</guid><description>We have all marveled at the astonishing feat of being able to hold up massive amounts of weight with only phonebooks. Mythbusters even went so far as to use tanks to try to pull apar the phone books. Since then, however, the origin of this phenomenon has remained very elusive and escaped full description.
It was first thought that the mechanism is due to the friction between interleaving pages. A new paper by Hector Alacron and colleagues1 finds that this explaination is incorrect and offer a more intuitive and more predictive explaination.</description></item><item><title>How does Bitcoin work?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/bitcoin/</guid><description>(Yes, yet another description of how Bitcoin works)
Why isn&amp;rsquo;t USD good enough anymore? Standard currencies like USD, Yen, Euro&amp;rsquo;s all have a central bank associated with them that can print and distribute money at their whim. Bitcoins are a special type of currency - a cryptocurrency that is completely decentralized. Instead of a bank manager looking over the system and injecting cash when needed, the decentralized currency system monitors and regulates itself!</description></item><item><title>How can cataracts be stopped?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/cataracts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/cataracts/</guid><description>Cataracts are the clouding of the lens in the eye which can lead to blindness or can severely impair sight. Cataracts are most commonly associated with age, but there are about 20 million people on Earth that were born with cataracts. The cause of these congenital cataracts are varied but most suggest that its the crystallin proteins themselves that get mutated. (1) The eye produces these crystallin proteins that are supposed to last a lifetime, so when they are mutated they become unstable and cause cataracts!</description></item><item><title>How can a protein tune the circadian rhythms by switching its fold?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/protein-switching/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/protein-switching/</guid><description>Proteins are central to biology. For the most part, proteins in the body are crucial for catalyzing reactions that carry out almost all of our biologial processes. For a protein to be useful, after it&amp;rsquo;s made by a ribosome, it needs to fold into a 3-dimensional structure that is unique to its sequence.
Its been widely thought that every unique sequence corresponds to a single unique structure. However, in biology, there are always exceptions to the rule.</description></item><item><title>How do ants survive in the heat in the Sahara desert?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/ants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/ants/</guid><description>There is a class of ants that survive in the Sahara desert despite it being one of the hottest places on Earth, where the surface temperature can reach up to 150 degrees Fahrenheit. These ants, called &amp;ldquo;silver ants&amp;rdquo; or Cataglyphis bombycina have recently been found to harbor specialized triangular hairs that enable them significantly increased thermoregulation, as reported in the recent issue of Science. [1] Though the surface of the desert exceeds 150F, the ants can keep an internal temperature of 120F.</description></item><item><title>How is the brain like a ball of crumpled paper?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/brain-folds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/brain-folds/</guid><description>This paper shows that the crumpling of our brain is much simpler than we thought . The crumples in our brain are just like the ones in crumpled paper. Bruno Mota and Suzana Herculano-Houzel find that our brain shares something in common with crumbled balls of paper - both did not evolve their folds in response to natural selection of their environment.
So what? This paper shows that the crumpling of our brain is much simpler than we thought.</description></item><item><title>How similar is animal language to human language?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/animal-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/animal-language/</guid><description>Language is an extremly important aspects of our human lives, and its aquisition might be an innate part of our brain that separates us from animals. However, different animals can understand language on different levels, as noted by Steven Pinker in his book The Language Instinct:
The most receptive trainee for an artificial language with a syntax and semantics has been a parrot; the species with the best claim to recursive structure in its signaling has been the starling; the best vocal imitators are birds and dolphins; and when it comes to reading human intentions, chimps are bested by man&amp;rsquo;s best friend, Canis familiaris.</description></item><item><title>Protein folding, simulation vs. experiment</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/simulation-and-experiment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/simulation-and-experiment/</guid><description>Prigozhin et al. has brought simulations and experiments of protein dynamics closer together than ever before. They do this by creating a clever new protein that gives more detailed experimental insight and simulations on a state-of-the-art molecular dynamics supercomputer. Their insights add another brick into the path that scientists have been building for decades to bridge protein experiments and simulations. The only way to do this are through advances like this paper - creating experiments that are faster than ever before while creating simulations that can simulate reality for longer than ever before.</description></item><item><title>How do you make a brain from scratch?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/neuron-origin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/neuron-origin/</guid><description>No one knows where neurons, the basic of human thought, come from. They are thought to have evolved once throughout the animal kingdom and perfected ever since. However, the newly revealed DNA sequencing of a comb jelly called &amp;ldquo;Pacific sea gooseberry&amp;rdquo;1 indicates this is not the case, as it has evolved its own neural system independently of any other sea jelly.
)
So what? The brain is one of the most complex components of any anatomical system, maybe the most complicated thing in the universe - consisting of neurons, cerebral tissue, neurotransmitters, etc.</description></item><item><title>How can potential transplant donors be identified by their sense of smell?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/sense-of-smell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/sense-of-smell/</guid><description>Researchers discover a new way of discovering bone marrow transplants matches by using only their sense of smell! I just recently wrote about a recent discovery that find people can smell without their noses (hint they use their skin) . Well, a new article by Lavi Secundo et. al. finds that the nose is still useful, since the olfactory receptors in a nose are so unique that they can distinguish humans from one another and this distinction can be used to find bone marrow transplant donors!</description></item><item><title>How to evaluate the driving forces behind Bitcoin?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/bitcoin-forces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/bitcoin-forces/</guid><description>A recent article published in PloS ONE attempts to figure out the origin of the rise in value of bitcoin. [1] The author, Ladislav Kristoufek, dissects the most probable sources of Bitcoin valuation influences using a special technique - cross wavelet transforms. This technique decomposes signals into the frequency domain and allows one to look at correlations between two sets of time-series data over various cycle lengths (e.g. daily or monthly or yearly) over time.</description></item><item><title>How many ice cubes?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/ice-cubes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 09:43:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/ice-cubes/</guid><description>MathJax.Hub.Config({ tex2jax: { inlineMath: [[&#39;$&#39;,&#39;$&#39;], [&#39;\\(&#39;,&#39;\\)&#39;]], displayMath: [[&#39;$$&#39;,&#39;$$&#39;], [&#39;\[&#39;,&#39;\]&#39;]], processEscapes: true, processEnvironments: true, &#34;HTML-CSS&#34;: { linebreaks: { automatic: true } }, SVG: { linebreaks: { automatic: true } }, skipTags: [&#39;script&#39;, &#39;noscript&#39;, &#39;style&#39;, &#39;textarea&#39;, &#39;pre&#39;], TeX: { equationNumbers: { autoNumber: &#34;AMS&#34; }, extensions: [&#34;AMSmath.js&#34;, &#34;AMSsymbols.js&#34;] } } }); MathJax.Hub.Queue(function() { // Fix tags after MathJax finishes running. This is a // hack to overcome a shortcoming of Markdown.</description></item><item><title>How do worms help to describe human mortality?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/worm-mortality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/worm-mortality/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s very bold to invent a new word. Its even more bold to invent a new word and add that as a keyword of your science article! That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what Ankita Bansala, Lihua Zhua, Kelvin Yena, and Heidi Tissenbaumam did in their paper1 on which they question the value of the term &amp;ldquo;lifespan&amp;rdquo; and probe key assumptions using worms. Their newly invented term, gerospan, shows up about 34 times and, though they don&amp;rsquo;t say exactly where it comes from, it seems to be a mashup of the more common &amp;ldquo;lifespan&amp;rdquo; with the department of one of the authors (Gerontology, which means - literally - the study of old people).</description></item><item><title>How does your skin act like a nose?</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/skin-as-nose/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/skin-as-nose/</guid><description>We smell with our nose, or do we? Recently scientists have found that for some smells we can smell with our skin, and those smells can heal wounds. Our ability to smell requires olfactory receptors which are often found in the nose. Humans have about 400 of these receptors, 350 of which are in the nose, while others have been shown to exist in sperm, the prostate, intestines, and kidneys.</description></item></channel></rss>