<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coding on schollz blog</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/tags/coding/</link><description>Recent content in Coding on schollz blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 05:44:33 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://schollz.github.io/tags/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Read news in the terminal with Docker</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/docker-news/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 05:44:33 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/docker-news/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on readable, a simple bookmarklet for easily reading articles in the browser (Github). As part of this, I made a Docker image that utilizes Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s readability package.
You can easily use the Docker image to directly read articles from the command line.
First pull it.
$ docker pull schollz/readable Then set a URL that contains a news article:
$ URL=http://www.cnn.com/2017/10/03/world/nobel-physics-prize-2017/index.html Then read!
$ docker run --rm -t schollz/readable $URL | more ---------------------------------------------------------- Nobel Prize in Physics goes to &#39;black hole telescope&#39; trio ---------------------------------------------------------- Story highlights - The development proves Einstein&#39;s prediction of gravitational waves - More than 1,000 people worked on the technology over four decades (CNN)The 2017 Nobel Prize in Physics has been awarded to Rainer Weiss, Barry C.</description></item><item><title>OSS divisions</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/oss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 09:04:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/oss/</guid><description>There are two reasons I think its good for everyone to have a good division between &amp;ldquo;personal&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;corporate&amp;rdquo; use for open-source software (OSS):
1. If you, the OSS maintainer, are compensated, everyone benefits.
While your time spent coding your OSS is valuable, I think the frictionless delivery of new features and bug fixes is something that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go away.
Since I&amp;rsquo;m not actively supporting you financially to work on this, I can only hope that someone does so I can benefit.</description></item><item><title>Using Wordpress with Docker</title><link>https://schollz.github.io/wordpress-on-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 13:54:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://schollz.github.io/wordpress-on-docker/</guid><description>I like wordpress, but it is very intensive to get working, as it uses a lot of PHP and requires SQL. Of course, nowadays you can do everything in Docker, so here is my method for getting wordpress to work great on Docker.
Using Docker, I was able to get 2 blogs run on the smallest DigitalOcean droplet (which was already running two dozen other things). Each blog required 360MB of RAM, and the total Docker space was 3.</description></item></channel></rss>